<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-08-16T16:01:09+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Srikrishna Iyer, Senior Research Engineer </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Interpretable counterfactual explanations for object detection models using generative AI</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/CFEs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interpretable counterfactual explanations for object detection models using generative AI"/><published>2023-08-16T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-16T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/CFEs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/CFEs/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Explainable-AI,"/><category term="counterfactual-explanations,"/><category term="generative"/><category term="AI,"/><category term="computer"/><category term="vision"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recent times, deep vision models have gained extensive usage in safety-critical applications like autonomous driving, raising concerns about the interpretability of these models. Among various explanation techniques, counterfactual explanations are designed to identify small and understandable alterations to an input image that would lead to a different output from the model being explained. Such explanations highlight the key factors influencing the model's decision, aiding end-users in comprehending the decision-making process. However, existing methods face challenges when explaining decision models trained on complex images with multiple objects, such as urban scenes. These challenging images are both more intricate to work with and more crucial to explain. In this research, a solution is proposed to address this issue using an object-centric framework for generating counterfactual explanations. The method draws inspiration from recent generative modeling approaches and encodes the original image into a structured latent space that facilitates manipulation at the object level.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Self-supervised audio classification for water leakage detection.</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/audio-class/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-supervised audio classification for water leakage detection."/><published>2023-06-13T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-13T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/audio-class</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/audio-class/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="audio-classification,"/><category term="mel-spectrogram,"/><category term="self-supervised-classification,"/><category term="signal-processing,"/><category term="transformer,"/><category term="deep-learning"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Currently working on a self-supervised audio classification model using Transformers. The model trains on acoustic sensor data collected for over 2 years and can automatically detect and classify water leakage in the water distributions systems in Singapore.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Graph-Attention-based Time-Series Generative Adversarial Network</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/GAT-GAN/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Graph-Attention-based Time-Series Generative Adversarial Network"/><published>2023-06-03T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-03T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/GAT-GAN</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2023/GAT-GAN/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="generative-AI,"/><category term="spatio-temporal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[we propose a Graph-Attention-based Generative Adversarial Network (GAT-GAN) that explicitly includes two graph-attention layers, one that learns temporal dependencies while the other captures spatial relationships. Unlike RNN-based GANs that struggle with modeling long sequences of data points, GAT-GAN generates long time-series data of high fidelity using an adversarially trained autoencoder architecture. Our empirical evaluations, using a variety of real-time-series datasets, show that our framework consistently outperforms state-of-the-art benchmarks based on Frechet Transformer distance, a prposed standardized metric and Predictive score, a downstream forecasting performance metric, that characterizes (Fidelity, Diversity) and predictive performance respectively.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Multivariate spatio-temporal predictive maintenance using graph attention networks</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2022/MTAD-GAT/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Multivariate spatio-temporal predictive maintenance using graph attention networks"/><published>2022-12-31T15:53:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T15:53:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2022/MTAD-GAT</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2022/MTAD-GAT/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="graph-attention-networks,"/><category term="signal-processing,"/><category term="representation-learning,"/><category term="multivariate"/><category term="anomaly-detection,"/><category term="physics-based-user-behaviour-modelling"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A self-supervised predictive maintenance pipeline proposed for diesel engines which consists of a user-behaviour forecasting model, a diagnostic classification model and a model-agnostic explanablility module to interpret forecasted faults. Here, the forecasting model uses GANs to generate future user-behaviour before the start of the mission based on several categorical and continuous-valued inputs from real-world and simulated data.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quality prediction using ensemble-tree regressor</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2022/QA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quality prediction using ensemble-tree regressor"/><published>2022-05-01T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-01T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2022/QA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2022/QA/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="tree-ensemble,"/><category term="feature-engineering,"/><category term="signal-processing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed a tree-based ensemble learner to predict constructive and destructive quality measurement criteria for all units in wirebond production (A semiconductor packaging process) using multimodal sensor data (vision,ultrasonic,pressure,force etc.). Based on a hold-out test set, the proposed model minimized the normalized root mean square error by ~19% in comparison to the next best baseline performance. The model allowed our customers to predict quality measurement on 100% of units produced without destructive tests. During my time working on the project, the model was deployed as part of a smart manufacturing data analytics solution which allowed the company to earn a revenue of ~ 1million$.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wireless blood pressure monitoring system using a dual milli-meter wave radar system and machine learning</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2020/vital-signs-BP/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wireless blood pressure monitoring system using a dual milli-meter wave radar system and machine learning"/><published>2020-07-01T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-01T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2020/vital-signs-BP</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2020/vital-signs-BP/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="radar-signal-processing,"/><category term="machine-learning"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed and implemented an efficient mm-Wave FMCW radar-based non-invasive and non-contact vital signs (blood pressure) monitoring system using radar signal processing. A Gaussian SVM regressor was used to predict BP values using Pulse transit time (Time difference between consecutive R peaks) with an R squared value of 0.8 and 0.95 for systolic BP and diastolic BP respectively relative to the ground truth.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Structural health monitoring system for railway tracks</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2019/SHM/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Structural health monitoring system for railway tracks"/><published>2019-07-01T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-01T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2019/SHM</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2019/SHM/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="structural-health-monitoring,"/><category term="deep-learning,"/><category term="IoT-systems,"/><category term="computer-vision"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We propose a multi-robot system for railway track fault detection, replacing manual human inspection. Our hardware prototype includes a master-slave robot mechanism that detects surface defects like cracks, squats, corrugations, and rust using ultrasonic sensors and image processing with OpenCV and deep learning algorithms. Our Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) model outperforms other algorithms in accuracy, R-squared value, F1 score, and Mean-Squared Error (MSE). The system is extended to a multi-robot framework to optimize energy usage, prolong robot lifespan, and improve network throughput. We simulate the LEACH protocol with 100 robot nodes to evaluate performance metrics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Antlion optimization and Whale optimization Algorithm for multilevel thresholding segmentation</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2019/image-opt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Antlion optimization and Whale optimization Algorithm for multilevel thresholding segmentation"/><published>2019-03-22T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2019/image-opt</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2019/image-opt/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="metaheuristic-optimization,"/><category term="image-segmentation,"/><category term="multilevel-thresholding"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[a practical comparison is made to deduce the best optimization technique amongst the whale optimization and antlion optimization algorithm, to solve the multilevel threshold problem, to find the optimal multilevel thresholds. Otsu's function is maximized to perform optimized thresholding-based image segmentation. The experimental results showed that the Antlion optimization algorithm gave better performance in solving the problem for higher level multi-thresholding.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Support Vector Machine based spectrum handoff scheme for seamless handover in Cognitive Radio Networks</title><link href="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2018/Cog-radios/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Support Vector Machine based spectrum handoff scheme for seamless handover in Cognitive Radio Networks"/><published>2018-06-01T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2018/Cog-radios</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://srikrish010697.github.io/blog/2018/Cog-radios/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="cogntive-radio,"/><category term="dynamic-spectrum-sharing,"/><category term="machine-learning,"/><category term="spectrum-handoff"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We implement a spectrum handoff method using classical machine learning algorithms in cogntivie radio networks. Spectrum scarcity is one of the major limitations causing hardships in the existing wireless networks. Cognitive Radio Networks (CRNs) emerge as a solution to tide over such humps. The ML algorithm will allow CRNs to predict the ideal channel for unlicensed users to switch back to when the licensed user claims back the unused spectrum.]]></summary></entry></feed>